<entry>
    <title>Criticisms of the Constitution</title>
    <subtitle>Consitutional Shortcomings</subtitle>
    <extraInfo></extraInfo>
    <notes>These are documented opinions, and should be read as such</notes>
    <mainInfo>
        <section>
            <title></title>
            <text>Several academics have criticized the Constitution for specific shortcomings. University of Virginia professor Larry Sabato wants an amendment to organize primaries to prevent a "frontloaded calendar" long before the election to prevent a "race by states to the front of the primary pack" which subverts the national interest, in his view. Sabato details more objections in his book A More Perfect Constitution. Richard Labunski agrees with Sabato about the "incoherent organization of primaries and caucuses," and faults the Constitution for enabling presidents to continue unpopular wars, for requiring presidents to be "natural born citizens", for lifetime tenure for Supreme Court judges which "produces senior judges representing the views of past generations better than views of the current day." He writes "If the 26 least populated states voted as a bloc, they would control the U.S. Senate with a total of just under 17% of the country's population."&#10;&#10;University of Texas law professor Sanford Levinson also wonders whether it makes sense to give "Wyoming the same number of votes as California, which has roughly seventy times the population". He thinks this imbalance causes a "steady redistribution of resources from large states to small states." Levinson is critical of the electoral college since it allows the possibility of electing presidents who do not win the majority of votes. Three times in American history, presidents have been elected by the electoral college despite failing to win the popular vote: 1876 (Rutherford B. Hayes), 1888 (Benjamin Harrison) and 2000 (George W. Bush). The current Constitution does not give the people a quick way to remove incompetent or ill presidents, in his view. Others have criticized the politically driven redistricting process popularly known as gerrymandering.&#10;&#10;Yale professor Robert A. Dahl sees a problem with an American tendency towards worship of the Constitution itself, and sees aspects of American governance which are "unusual and potentially undemocratic: the federal system, the bicameral legislature, judicial review, presidentialism, and the electoral college system." Levinson and Labunski and others have called for a Second Constitutional Convention, although professors like Dahl believe there is no real hope this might ever happen.</text>
        </section>
    </mainInfo>
    <wikipedia>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_Constitution#Criticism_of_the_Constitution</wikipedia>
    <google>http://www.google.com/search?q=us+constitution+criticisms</google>
    <official>http://wiki.answers.com/Q/What_was_the_major_criticisms_of_the_Constitution_as_drafted_in_Philadelphia</official>
</entry>