<entry>
    <title>Unratified Amendments</title>
    <subtitle>Did not pass the vote</subtitle>
    <notes>Of the thirty-three amendments that have been proposed by Congress, six have failed ratification by the required three-quarters of the state legislatures, and four of those six are still technically pending before state lawmakers (see Coleman v. Miller). Starting with the 18th Amendment, each proposed amendment has included a deadline for passage, except the 19th Amendment (women's voting) and the Child Labor Amendment, proposed in 1924 and still unratified.</notes>
    <mainInfo>
        <section>
            <title>The Congressional Apportionment Amendment</title>
            <text>Defined a formula for how many members there would be in the United States House of Representatives after each decennial census. Ratified by eleven states, the last being Kentucky in June 1792 during Kentucky's initial month of statehood, this amendment contains no expiration date for ratification. In principle it may yet be ratified, though as written it became irrelevant when the population of the United States reached ten million.</text>
	    <extraInfo>Proposed by the 1st Congress on September 25, 1789</extraInfo>
            <notes></notes>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Titles of Nobility Amendment</title>
            <text>Would have ended the citizenship of any American accepting "any Title of Nobility or Honour" from any foreign power. Some maintain that the amendment was ratified by the legislatures of enough states, and that a conspiracy has suppressed it, but this has been thoroughly debunked. Known to have been ratified by lawmakers in twelve states, the last in 1812, this amendment contains no expiration date for ratification. It may yet be ratified.</text>
	    <extraInfo>Proposed by the 11th Congress on May 1, 1810</extraInfo>
            <notes></notes>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>The Corwin Amendment</title>
            <text>Would have forbidden any attempt to subsequently amend the Constitution to empower the federal government to "abolish or interfere" with the "domestic institutions" of the states (a delicate way of referring to slavery). It was ratified by only Ohio and Maryland lawmakers before the outbreak of the Civil War. Illinois lawmakers—sitting as a state constitutional convention at the time—likewise approved it, but that action is of questionable validity. The proposed amendment contains no expiration date for ratification and may yet be ratified. However, adoption of the 13th, 14th, and 15th Amendments after the Civil War likely means that the amendment would be ineffective if adopted.</text>
	    <extraInfo>Proposed by the 36th Congress on March 2, 1861</extraInfo>
            <notes></notes>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Child Labor Amendment</title>
            <text>"The Congress shall have power to limit, regulate, and prohibit the labor of persons under eighteen years of age." This amendment is highly unlikely to be ratified, since subsequent federal child labor laws have uniformly been upheld as a valid exercise of Congress's powers under the Commerce Clause.</text>
	    <extraInfo>Proposed by the 68th Congress on June 2, 1924</extraInfo>
            <notes></notes>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>The Equal Rights Amendment</title>
            <text>"Equality of rights under the law shall not be denied or abridged by the United States or by any state on account of sex." Proposed by the 92nd Congress on March 22, 1972, it was ratified by the legislatures of 35 states, and expired on either March 22, 1979 or on June 30, 1982, depending upon one's point of view of a controversial three-year extension of the ratification deadline, which was passed by the 95th Congress in 1978. Of the 35 states ratifying it, four later rescinded their ratifications before the extended ratification period which began on March 23, 1979 and a fifth, while not going so far as to rescind its earlier ratification, adopted a resolution stipulating that its approval would not extend beyond March 22, 1979. There continues to be disagreement over whether such reversals are valid; no court has ruled on the question, including the Supreme Court. A precedent against the validity of rescission was first established during the ratification process of the 14th Amendment when Ohio and New Jersey rescinded their earlier approvals, but yet were counted as ratifying states when the 14th Amendment was ultimately proclaimed part of the Constitution in 1868.</text>
	    <extraInfo>Proposed by the 92nd Congress on March 22, 1972</extraInfo>
            <notes></notes>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>The District of Columbia Voting Rights Amendment</title>
            <text>Had this amendment been ratified, it would have granted to Washington, D.C. two Senators and at least one member of the House of Representatives as though the District of Columbia were a state. Ratified by the legislatures of only 16 states (out of the required 38), the proposed amendment expired on August 22, 1985</text>
	    <extraInfo>Proposed by the 95th Congress on August 22, 1978</extraInfo>
            <notes></notes>
        </section>
    </mainInfo>
    <wikipedia>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Unratified_amendments_to_the_United_States_Constitution</wikipedia>
    <google>http://www.google.com/search?q=us+constitution+unratified+amendments</google>
    <official>http://www.usconstitution.net/constamfail.html</official>
</entry>